# Jose Antonio Torres

# Software Engineer

Boca Raton, FL | jose.torres8672@icloud.com | 561-287-0658 | Github.com/vidojam

# **Professional Summary**

A client-focused professional with a diverse background in customer service, financial sales, and software development. Over **5**+ years of software engineering experience. Spent a decade as a State of Florida Business Specialist, successfully planning, coordinating, and executing recruitment events for **150**+ employers per year.

### **Education**

Boca CodeBoca Raton, FLSoftware Engineering Career Course (FERN/MERN)Mar 2023 - May 2023

NuCamp

Fullstack Web Developer (MERN)

Boca Raton, FL
Sept 2021 - Feb 2022

Academy of South Florida

Coral Springs, FL

Microsoft MCITP, Windows 7, Server 2008 R2

Chubb Institute

Mar 2011 - Sept 2011

Jersey City, NJ

Software Programming, Cobol, ASM400, VSAM. Sept 1995 - Feb 1996

# **Projects**

#### Evaluator Assistant - Web Based React App REPO | LIVE

May 2023

• Developed a web-based application using **React** that evaluates speakers for a public speaking club, providing a user-friendly interface for assessing and managing speaker information.

#### **Work Experience**

# Business Development Specialist CareerSource Broward

Hollywood, FL

Feb 2012 – Feb 2022

- Achieved successful employer mass recruitments both on and off site as a Recruitment Specialist, resulting in the placement of **500**+ job seekers.
- Efficiently coordinated job fair activities per year, attracting over **150**+ employers per year generating a high volume of attendees and facilitating productive connections between job seekers and employers.
- Played a pivotal role as a member of the CareerSource Broward Rapid Response Team, providing support to **400**+ dislocated workers affected by State of Florida WARN notices. Actively facilitated their career transition and offered essential assistance, resulting in positive outcomes for the individuals.

# **Integrated Business Systems (IBS)**

Fairfield, NJ Sep 1996 – Oct 1997

**Software Support** 

- Provided software training and support to over **100**+ real estate management companies in New York and New Jersey, using Integrated Business Systems (IBS) proprietary accounting software.
- Effectively assessed client needs and provided appropriate recommendations, directing them to the appropriate IT support and sales channels for both software and hardware solutions.

# **Promoted: Software Administration Manager**

Oct 1997 – Aug 2001

- Successfully managed and executed software updates, version upgrades, and program patches for a company of 40+ employees, ensuring the smooth functioning and security of the software systems.
- Received an award in the year 2000 for a record of smooth and orderly software updates within a **6 month** period.

# **Technical Skills**

**Programming Languages**: Javascript | Typescript | Python | C# | HTML | CSS

**Technologies**: React | React Native | AWS | Express | Git, Bash

Languages: Fluent in English & Spanish